Isaiah Hayes

5347 Sunlight Place Los Angeles, California 90016 Phone: (323) 933-2615 • Cell: (310) 733-8884 • E-Mail: IsaiahWHayes@Gmail.com

Summary

With eight years of QA experience across mobile, web, desktop applications, tablets, AR (augmented reality), VR (virtual reality) and game console platforms, I've helped deliver hundreds of successful projects in various industries. I've used manual and light automation-based tests to lead bi-coastal Quality Assurance teams of 2-8 members to successful project releases for Audi, Boeing, Raytheon, Intel, Dell, Google, Activision/Blizzard, Nintendo of America and many popular App / Google Play store applications.

Experience

Sr. Quality Assurance Engineer – Planet Art LLC

2019 - Present

- I collaborate cross-departmentally with Marketing Managers, front-end engineers, back-end engineers and Project Managers to assure the quality of all campaigns in regard to regional accuracy, language, cultural acceptance and more...
- Manage quality assurance sprints, regressions, and bug tracking databases for seven (7) App Store (iOS) and Google Play Store (Android) applications available for download in 9 different countries.
- Create and perform manual front-end and back-end tests for new features as they progress through the software development life cycle from pre-production to delivery.
- QA tools used: Jira, Confluence, Tunnel Bear, various proxy servers, version control databases (hockeyapp and app center), proprietary backend databases and admin tools, and more.

Quality Assurance Lead – Inhance Digital Corporation 2016 - 2019

- Devise methods of execution to address QA needs in regard to time, budget, technological hardware/software, and available resources.
- Guide QA pre-production efforts by structuring manual test plans and test suites that streamline common content, stability, performance and functional tests.
- Spearheaded Inhance's first virtual reality contract, generating over \$250,000 in revenue within a 2 week turn-around time.
- Spearheaded Inhance's first artificial intelligence retail simulation, generating a \$75,000 profit within a turn-around time of 1 month.
- Using Jira and Bugzilla bug tracking systems, I've effectively and efficiently managed over 450 projects totaling thousands of reported application issues (bugs).
- Client facing representative for out-of-state business events, tradeshows, client showcases, tech conferences and more.
- Client examples: Harris Corporation, Honeywell International Inc., Raytheon, Boeing, Intel, Dell and more.
- Furthered Inhance's QA efforts and improved business efficiency by implementing a more frequent use of automated tests using Sikuli X and Python.



- Led agile teams of 4-8 employees to successful video game releases for clients such as Nintendo, PlayStation, Microsoft, Kixeye and more.
- Structured training programs for junior testers in the following areas: localization, compliance, regression, compatibility, functionality, and loading tests.
- Part-time liaison between clients and in-house quality assurance teams.
- Established a bug writing structure that was later adopted by our Nintendo of America clients.
- Managed over 20,000 reported issues in BugZilla, Mantis, and Nintendo's VPN databases.
- 2 years of Android and Apple mobile testing.

Founder | Production Director - CoastLine Music Group, LLC 2013 - 2019

- Lead a team of composers, producers and engineers to successfully complete television and indie film music projects for Inhance Digital Corporation.
- Facilitated a distribution partnership to release music on streaming services such as iTunes, Spotify,
 Pandora, Tidal and others in order to increase national and international exposure.
- Web designer, and project manager for all photo and video assets produced and displayed on www.CoastLineMusicGroup.com.

Technology Specialist – Best Buy Co., Inc.

2009 - 2012

- Increased product and service conversion rates by 10%.
- Three-time award winning "90% or better Mystery Shop Score" employee.
- "Deterring Loss" award winning employee.

Temporary Quality Assurance Tester – Activision Inc. 2007 - 2009

- "Triple A" game title tester: Call of Duty: World at War, Guitar Hero: Aerosmith, Guitar Hero: Metallica, Band Hero, and James Bond: Quantum of Solace.
- Two years of intense training in the DevTrack data management system.

Education

Coding Dojo: Bootcamp 2020

<u>Software Development</u>: Full Stack Development

Full Sail University 2018

Master of Science: Entertainment Business

Full Sail University 2017

• Bachelor of Science: Music Production

West Los Angeles College

2008

• Web Programming: (HTML / CSS)

Alexander Hamilton high school

2007

• <u>High School Diploma</u>: Emphasis on Electronic Music

Relevant Course Work

College Mathematics: A+ Advanced Entertainment Law: A

Entertainment Business Finance: A Executive Leadership: B+

Project and Team Management: A Computer Programming: B

Certifications

certifications and the second			
•	JavaScript Essential Training Lynda.com, License EFF92F	2017	
•	Learning the JavaScript Language Lynda.com, License 02DDB9	2017	
•	Programming Foundations: Databases Lynda.com, License E99E13	2017	
•	Programming Foundations: Fundamentals Lynda.com, License 35DF8C	2017	